Previously on the show.
ความเดิมตอนที่แล้ว
Weslie’s mark activated new functions of the Magic Train
ปานเวทย์ของเวสลี่ ทำให้รถไฟวิเศษเปิดใช้งานระบบใหม่ขึ้น
and defeated Wolffy.
และเอาชนะวูฟฟี่ได้
After bidding farewell to the residents of Tower Town,
หลังจากกล่าวลาผู้อาศัยในเมืองหอคอย
Weslie continues his journey on the Magic Train to find his friends.
เวสลี่ก็ขึ้นรถไฟวิเศษออกเดินทาง ตามหาเพื่อนๆ ต่อไป
Will he successfully reunite with his friends?
เวสลี่จะได้กลับไปเจอเพื่อนๆ อีกครั้งรึเปล่า
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Weather Factory."
"แกะน้อยสุดกวนกับหมาป่าจอมป่วน ตอน โรงงานกำเนิดฤดูกาล"
I’m really close to the destination on the radar.
ถ้าดูจากเรดาร์ก็ใกล้ถึงแล้วล่ะ
I wonder who I’ll find over there.
สงสัยจังว่าจะเจอใครที่นั่นบ้างนะ
What a huge tree!
ต้นไม้อะไรจะใหญ่ปานนี้เนี่ย!
What’s that thing flying towards me?
อะไรพุ่งตรงเข้ามาหาเราเนี่ย
Oh, no!
โอ้แย่ล่ะสิ!
Wow, an aurora?
ว้าว แสงเหนือเหรอเนี่ย
We have an emergency! The aurora fruit was intercepted.
เกิดเหตุฉุกเฉิน! มีเครื่องบินขวางทางลำเลียงลูกแสงเหนือ
Stop that aircraft immediately.
หยุดเครื่องบินลำนั้นเดี๋ยวนี้เลย
Attention! Please descend immediately.
โปรดทราบ! กรุณานำเครื่องลงทันที!
Uh, what happened?
เอ่อ... เกิดอะไรขึ้นเนี่ย
Uh, excuse me, could you tell me what this place is?
โทษทีฮะ บอกทีได้ไหมว่าที่นี่ที่ไหนฮะ
This is Weather City.
ที่นี่คือเมืองกำเนิดฤดูกาล
And that facility right ahead...
อาคารที่เห็นอยู่ด้านหน้านั่น... คือโรงงานกำเนิดฤดูกาล
This is where our weather is created.
ที่นี่คือต้นกำเนิดฤดูกาลต่างๆ
This place is huge!
ที่นี่ใหญ่จังเลย!
Come on in.
เข้ามาสิ
Boss, he’s the one intercepting the weather fruits.
หัวหน้า เจ้านี่แหละที่ขวางทางลำเลียงลูกสี่ฤดู
Shall we inform the director?
เราแจ้งท่านผอ.เลยดีไหม
No, of course not.
ไม่ได้นะๆ
Let’s not bother the director with this unimportant thing.
อย่าเอาเรื่องไม่สำคัญไปรบกวนท่านผอ.เลย
We can just handle it ourselves.
เราจัดการกันเองก็ได้
You’re right.
หัวหน้าพูดถูก
Hello. My name is Weslie, sir.
หวัดดีฮะ ผมชื่อเวสลี่ฮะ
So, you’re the one intercepting the weather fruits?
นายก็คือแกะที่ขวางทางลำเลียงลูกสี่ฤดูใช่ไหม
Weather… fruit?
ลูกสี่ฤดูเหรอฮะ
This… is a weather fruit.
นี่ไงล่ะ นี่คือลูกสี่ฤดู
Come and follow me.
ตามฉันมาสิ
Look.
ดูนะ
Weather fruits are an important resource of Weather City.
ลูกสี่ฤดูคือทรัพยากรสำคัญ ของเมืองกำเนิดฤดูกาล
They come from the weather tree.
พวกมันมาจากต้นสี่ฤดูไงล่ะ
The weather fruits come in three sizes.
ลูกสี่ฤดูมีอยู่สามขนาดด้วยกัน
There are large, medium, and small-sized fruits.
มีลูกขนาดใหญ่ กลาง และเล็ก
When the weather fruits ripen,
เมื่อลูกสี่ฤดูสุกแล้ว
the pelicans come and pick them.
พวกนกกระทุงจะมาเก็บพวกมันไป
They will then transport the fruits to the factory.
พวกนกจะเอาผลไม้นั่นไปส่งที่โรงงาน
At the factory,
ที่โรงงาน...
the fruits go through the process of washing,
ผลไม้จะเข้าสู่ขบวนการล้าง
drying,
เป่าแห้ง
and waxing.
เคลือบขี้ผึ้ง
Finally, they get sorted by machines,
สุดท้ายจะถูกส่งเข้าเครื่องจักรเพื่อคัดขนาด
and delivered to our residents.
และส่งต่อไปยังผู้อาศัยของเรา
I want some shaved ice...
หนูอยากกินน้ำแข็งไส...
This is the weather fruits you ordered.
ลูกสี่ฤดูที่สั่งไว้มาแล้วครับ
Oh, thank you very much.
โอ้ ขอบคุณมากนะ
The small ones are useful in our daily life.
พวกลูกเล็กๆ มีประโยชน์ไว้ใช้ในชีวิตประจำวัน
The medium ones are good for cleaning our streets.
พวกลูกขนาดกลางก็ดีสำหรับทำความสะอาดถนน
But all that is just what we do on the side.
แต่ทั้งหมดนั่นคืองานเสริมนะ
What the factory actually does is to create weather!
จริงๆ แล้วสิ่งที่โรงงานนี้ทำ คือสร้างฤดูกาลต่างๆ ไงล่ะ!
Oh… I see.
อ๋อ เข้าใจแล้วฮะ
Have a look.
ลองดูสิ
Are those the large weather fruits?
พวกนั้นคือลูกสี่ฤดูลูกใหญ่เหรอฮะ
That’s correct.
ใช่แล้วล่ะ
The large weather fruits are transported to the top of the factory by machines
ลูกสี่ฤดูลูกใหญ่จะถูกเครื่องจักร ส่งขึ้นไปอยู่บนสุดของโรงงาน
and then launched to every corner of the world through cannons,
จากนั้นปืนใหญ่จะส่งผลไม้นั่นไปยังทั่วทุกมุมโลก
forming different weather patterns.
ทำให้เกิดรูปแบบสภาพอากาศที่แตกต่างกัน
What you hit earlier was a big weather fruit just like one of these.
ที่นายไปชนเข้าก็คือลูกสี่ฤดูลูกใหญ่นี่แหละ
How about I grow a new one to compensate you?
ผมปลูกต้นใหม่คืนให้ได้ไหมฮะ
That’s fine. But the one you hit earlier was…
ไม่เป็นไร แต่ลูกที่นายชนไปก่อนหน้านี้...
our rare aurora fruits.
คือลูกแสงเหนือที่หายากน่ะสิ
We only harvest one batch per year.
ปีหนึ่งเราเก็บเกี่ยวได้แค่ครั้งเดียว
So, if you’re really serious about growing one,
แต่ถ้านายพูดจริงเรื่องจะปลูกต้นไม้คืนให้ล่ะก็
you will need to stay here for one year.
นายจำเป็นต้องอยู่ที่นี่หนึ่งปีเลยนะ
One year?
หนึ่งปีเลยเหรอฮะ
Where in the world is this place?
ที่นี่มันที่ไหนกันนะ
Wolffy, why are you taking so long?
วูฟฟี่ ทำไมชักช้าอยู่นั่นแหละ
I’m coming!
มาแล้วจ้ะ!
There you go again. What’s that thing you’re holding?
เอาอีกแล้วนะ คุณถืออะไรอยู่น่ะ
It’s an energy extractor! With this,
ปืนดูดพลังเวทย์ไงล่ะ! ถ้ามีเจ้านี่...
I’ll be able to take the gem back from the goats.
ผมก็จะเอาเพชรเลอค่ากลับมาจากพวกแกะได้
The question is... can you even catch the goats?
คำถามคือ... คุณจะจับพวกแกะได้รึเปล่าล่ะ
Dad, Mom, look over here!
พ่อฮะ แม่ฮะ มาดูทางนี้สิฮะ!
These fruits look so special.
ผลไม้พวกนี้ดูสวยเป็นพิเศษเลยนะฮะ
Yes, they are.
ใช่ สวยเป็นพิเศษจริงๆ ด้วย
Why did it suddenly light up?
ทำไมอยู่ดีๆ ก็มีแสงออกมาล่ะ
Wolffy!
วูฟฟี่!
Ah, Wolnie!
เอ่อ โวลนี่!
Uh, the fruits in this place are very strange.
ผลไม้ของที่นี่แปลกจังเลย
Better not touch them.
อย่าไปจับพวกมันดีกว่านะ
What is it this time?
คราวนี้อะไรอีกล่ะ
Wolffy!
วูฟฟี่!
I… I think I’ll go catch goats!
ผมคิดว่าขอตัวไปจับพวกแกะก่อนดีกว่านะ!
Weslie, why don’t you start by working with Jackie here.
เวสลี่ ทำไมไม่ลองไปทำงานกับแจ็กกี้ดูล่ะ
Uhm.
ก็ได้ฮะ
Before we start, I’ll get a protective vest for you to wear.
ก่อนจะเริ่มงาน ฉันจะไปเอาเสื้อชูชีพให้นายใส่
Why do I need one?
ทำไมฉันต้องใส่ด้วยล่ะ
Because it’s dangerous here in the factory.
เพราะที่โรงงานนี่อันตรายน่ะสิ
The vest protects us while we work,
เสื้อกั๊กช่วยป้องกันเราตอนทำงาน
so we won’t get hurt from the effects of weather fruits.
เราจะได้ไม่บาดเจ็บจาก ผลกระทบที่ได้ของลูกสี่ฤดู
Oh, that’s amazing!
แบบนั้นก็วิเศษไปเลย!
Here. This one is yours.
เอาไป นี่ของนาย
Mister Jackie, do you know if there’s any equipment
คุณแจ็กกี้ รู้ไหมว่ามีอะไร...
that can make the aurora fruits grow faster?
ที่ทำให้ลูกแสงเหนือโตเร็วขึ้นไหม
Listen, young man, we have to do things step by step.
ฟังนะหนุ่มน้อย เราต้องทำอะไรตามขั้นตอน เรื่องพวกนี้จะเร่งรีบไม่ได้
You have to experience the process like you’re savoring life.
นายต้องเรียนรู้ทีละขั้นตอน เหมือนเรียนรู้รสชาติการใช้ชีวิต
So you should wait and work here for an entire year.
ดังนั้นนายควรจะรอและทำงานที่นี่สักปีนึง
Stop thinking about it.
เลิกคิดเรื่องนั้นเถอะ
Come on. Why don’t you just help me move these packages out?
ไปกันเถอะ ทำไมนายไม่ช่วยฉันขนของพวกนี้ออกไปล่ะ
Why are there so many of them?
ทำไมถึงมีของเยอะแยะแบบนี้ล่ะฮะ
If I have to work here for a year,
ถ้าฉันต้องทำงานที่นี่หนึ่งปี
how... how can I find my friends?
แล้วฉันจะไปตามหาเพื่อนๆ ได้ยังไงล่ะ
It would be great if they’re working in this factory too.
ถ้าเพื่อนๆ ทำงานที่โรงงานนี้ด้วยก็ดีน่ะสิ
But that’s just... impossible.
แต่เรื่องนั้นคงเป็นไปไม่ได้
I can take a break after I’m done with this box.
พอส่งกล่องนี้เสร็จก็พักได้แล้ว
Did I just see Weslie?
นี่ฉันเพิ่งเห็นเวสลี่รึเปล่านะ
Maybe I’m just hallucinating.
สงสัยจะตาฝาดไปน่ะ
Okay, it’s time to get back to work.
โอเค ได้เวลากลับไปทำงานแล้ว
Where could you guys be?
พวกนายไปอยู่ที่ไหนกันนะ
Hey, have you heard?
นี่ นายได้ยินไหม มีสัตว์บกจากอีกเมืองมาที่โรงงานของเรา
Yeah, I heard. The new guy said he was from some grassland.
ได้ยินสิ หนุ่มน้อยที่เพิ่งมาใหม่ บอกว่ามาจากดินแดนสีเขียว
Excuse me, was it Green-Green Grassland?
โทษทีฮะ ใช่ทุ่งหญ้าเขียวขจีรึเปล่า
Yes, that’s right.
ใช่แล้วล่ะ เขาบอกว่ามาจากที่ที่เรียกว่าทุ่งหญ้าเขียวขจี
Where is that person now?
หนุ่มน้อยคนนั้นอยู่ไหนแล้วฮะ
I think he’s at the warehouse in area 11.
ฉันคิดว่าเขาอยู่ที่โกดัง11 นะ
Thank you so much.
ขอบคุณมากฮะ
This is the place.
ที่นี่แหละ
Who is it?
ใครฮะ
Hey, Weslie, why don’t you eat something first?
เวสลี่ ทำไมนายไม่กินอะไรก่อนล่ะ
Thank you very much, Mister Jackie.
ขอบคุณมากฮะ คุณแจ็กกี้
The birds were quite helpful.
พวกนกนี่ช่วยได้เยอะเลยนะ
They told me there were goats in this place.
พวกนกบอกว่ามีพวกแกะอยู่ที่นี่
Wolffy... Wolffy is here!
วูฟฟี่! วูฟฟี่อยู่ที่นี่!
No shouting and running in the factory during working hours.
ช่วงเวลาทำงานห้ามตะโกนและวิ่งในโรงงาน
-Excuse me! -Stop!
- ขอทางหน่อย! - หยุดนะ!
No shouting and running in the factory.
ห้ามตะโกนและวิ่งในโรงงานสิ!
I wonder how everyone is now.
ตอนนี้ทุกคนจะเป็นยังไงกันบ้างนะ
What if one of them is in danger?
ถ้ามีใครสักคนตกอยู่ในอันตรายล่ะ
When can I find them?
ฉันจะไปหาพวกเขาได้ที่ไหนนะ
Uh, is that you, Paddi?
แพดดี้ นั่นนายรึเปล่า
Ha! Weslie!
เวสลี่นี่นา!
That was really you who I saw this morning.
ที่เห็นเมื่อเช้าก็คือเวสลี่จริงๆ ด้วย!
It really is you.
ใช่เวสลี่จริงๆ ด้วย
How come you’re here too?
นายมาอยู่ที่นี่เหมือนกันได้ไงเนี่ย
I’ve been waiting forever for you guys.
ผมมารอทุกคนอยู่ที่นี่ตั้งนานแล้วฮะ
I thought you already gave up looking for me.
ผมคิดว่าทุกคนเลิกตามหาผมซะแล้ว
Oh, don’t be silly. Let’s go together and look for--
อย่าโง่ไปหน่อยเลย งั้นเราไปตามหา...
The other goats?
พวกแกะตัวอื่นๆ เหรอ
I almost forgot about Wolffy.
ผมเกือบลืมเรื่องวูฟฟี่ไปเลย!
Take my hand!
จับมือฉันไว้สิ!
I knew you’d have a mark too.
นึกแล้วว่านายต้องมีปานเวทย์นี้ด้วย
What are you going to do?
นายจะทำอะไรน่ะ
Extract the energy from the gem on your hand, of course.
ดูดพลังวิเศษจากปานเวทย์บนมือนายไงล่ะ
Wolffy!
วูฟฟี่!
Do you really think...
นายคิดจริงๆ รึว่า...
you can beat a supervillain like me?
นายจะเอาชนะสุดยอดวายร้ายอย่างฉันได้
Paddi, run!
แพดดี้ หนีเร็ว!
Weslie…
เวสลี่...
There’s nowhere for you to run.
ไม่มีทางหนีแล้วสินะ
It’s time, Paddi!
แพดดี้ ตอนนี้แหละลงมือได้เลย!
Again?
อีกแล้วเหรอ
Wait and see, goats.
ฝากไว้ก่อนเถอะเจ้าพวกแกะ
I’ll be back!
ฉันต้องกลับมาแก้แค้นพวกนายแน่!
TO BE CONTINUED 2783 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
(โปรดติดตามต่อไป)